FORD HENLEY

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & DIGITAL MARKETER









EDUCATION

MARKETING Alabama 2005 - 2009

INTERNET MARKETING Full Sail University 2014

> .NET WEB DEVELOPMENT Coder Foundry AUG. 2022

> FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT BETHEL TECH SEPT. 2022

SKILLS

Google Analytics

Click Funnels

Web Development

SFO

Email Marketing

WordPress

Customer Service

Node.js/MongoDB/Unit Testing

HTML/CSS3/JavaScript

Typescript/React/PHP

PROFILE

Web Manager with 10 years of experience in web development, digital marketing, and analytics. Delivered website speed performance improvements for a Google Page Speed Score for over 50 WordPress & Drupal sites. Produced custom data reports for 3 Sport Clips Franchises along with campaign performance reports for 25 clients. Ranked over 10 clients and employers #1 on Google for their desired keywords.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL STRATEGIST

Sport Clips (Franchise), Okaloosa County, FL | 2015 - Present

- Lead business development activities, research current and future target markets.
- Work with Team Leader to manage marketing projects and improve business efficiency through using automations and technology.
- Headed creation of support ticket systems to manage multistore issues and standardize monthly store success checks for quality assurance.
- Increased Destin location sales by 10% with strategic marketing partnerships to drive more traffic to the tourist-heavy economy via online advertising & social media.

PRESIDENT

Ford's Web Help, Fort Walton Beach, FL | 2017 - 2022

- Provide clients with custom designed solutions to drive revenue, create consistent branding, and streamline workflows.
- Gather requirements for digital marketing initiatives and plan project scope.
- Design, launch, test, and deliver websites, while providing key updates to stakeholders and clients along with optimizing for searching engines.
- Manage all small business operations, including marketing, contract negotiations, and finances.

MARKETING DIRECTOR

The Shops at Wright Plaza, Fort Walton Beach, FL | 2015-2018

- Worked collaboratively with the rental unit manager to incorporate modern technology and develop a competitive web presence in all tenant stores.
- Developed New Brand Identity: created a new logo and website for the Shops at Wright Plaza.
- Coordinated digital displays with new tenant promotional information for monthly advertising on billboards and store reader-boards.

FORD HENLEY

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & DIGITAL MARKETER







fordp86@gmail.com

ACCOLADES

PRESIDENT'S CLUB Sport Clips 2013-2019

CHAIRMAN'S CLUB Sport Clips 2018

FINEST WEB DEVELOPER Finest on the Emerald Coast 2016

WEBSITE COMMITTEE
All Sports
Association
Okaloosa County, FL
2015-2021

WEBSITE CHAIR SIGMA PI FRATERNITY University of Alabama

INTERESTS

CrossFit

Rugby

Hiking

Designing Websites

Digital Marketing

Writing

Strategy & Trivia

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONT.

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Student Life/Lifeway Christian Resources, Birmingham, AL | 2012 - 2014

- Collaborated with creative teams and project managers to align priorities, organize duties, and implement new marketing campaigns with front end development.
- Converted all company websites to Twitter Bootstrap-based mobile-friendly sites to boost sales and traffic.
- Reduced monthly email marketing costs by 50% and increased efficiencies by migrating services from Constant Contact to Mailchimp
- Worked alongside the lead developer to create custom landing pages and content for company programs such as their Student Life Conference and Summer Camps

INTERNET MEDIA ASSOCIATE

ProctorU, Inc, Birmingham, AL | 2011 - 2012

- Promoted to Lead Tech Support Proctor within first two months.
- Promoted to Internet Media Associate after five months.
- Worked with CTO and CEO to develop ProctorU, Inc.'s initial internet marketing strategy as the first member of the web development team.
- Ranked #1 on Google for 'Online Proctoring'.
- Optimized their website to overtake existing competitors for the number one spot on Google for the highly competitive keywords: Online Proctoring and Virtual Proctoring.
- Made ProctorU, Inc. 508 ADA accessibility compliant.
- Partnered with the University of Illinois Accessibility program to make all of ProctorU, Inc.'s client facing web applications accessible to the visually impaired
- Developed a custom lead generation funnel to help separate new customers between the sales team and the support team.

PUBLIC RELATIONS INTERN

Silver Sands Factory Stores, Destin, FL | 2010

- Monitored and updated shopping center monthly media impressions in an Excel database
- Headed the design and developing for the company's entry for the FPRSA award
- Worked with 50 plus tenants to create monthly content for the shopping center's monthly shopper newsletter

FORD HENLEY

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & DIGITAL MARKETER



•

fordp86@gmail.com



Austin, TX



fordhenley.com

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

GOOGLE ADWORDS Google 2015

GOOGLE ANALYTICS
Google
2016

SCRUM MASTER Scrum Alliance 2018

Public Speaking Dale Carnegie Foundation

2003

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONT.

MARKETING INTERN
Boys & Girls Clubs of America, Atlanta, GA | 2009

- Managed the inventory database for the National HQ merchandise shop.
- Generated Press Releases and RFP's for marketing initiatives
- Managed the Ning Social Networking site for their new Day for Kids campaign
- Promoted a national training webinar cross channel marketing platforms such as email, newsletters, and direct response.

REFERENCES

TIM BAILEY
President
Territory 3
205.222.3118
tim@territory3.com

JACKLYN HEBERT Producer 2 Tall Women 850.428.2020 jackie@2tallwomen.com CARTER ZORN
President
All Sports Assoc.
334.524.1989
carter.zorn@gmail.com

JEFF McDONALD Loan Originator Prime Lending 850.499.4701 jeffmac25@mac.com